<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://simonzhu97.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://simonzhu97.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-08-21T03:30:39+00:00</updated><id>https://simonzhu97.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Simon Zhu’s Portfolio</title><subtitle>It&apos;s a personal portfolio website containing past projects and documentations. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Spotify Anime Music Recommender</title><link href="https://simonzhu97.github.io/blog/2022/Spotify-recommender/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spotify Anime Music Recommender"/><published>2022-05-20T21:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-05-20T21:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://simonzhu97.github.io/blog/2022/Spotify-recommender</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://simonzhu97.github.io/blog/2022/Spotify-recommender/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="background">Background</h2> <p>Anime is hand-drawn and computer animation originating from Japan. In Japan, anime describes all animated works, regardless of style or origin. However, outside of Japan, anime usually refers specifically to animation produced in Japan.</p> <p>Since the 1980s, this particular medium has witnessed great international success with the rise of subtitles and increasing distribution through streaming services. In fact, streaming services such as Netflix have invested quite some amount in this genre. In 2019, the annual overseas exports of Japanese animation exceeded $10 billion.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/spotify_icon-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/spotify_icon-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/spotify_icon-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/spotify_icon.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <h2 id="vision">Vision</h2> <p>Despite rapid growth of overseas exports, stigmas about anime still linger. Take anime music as an example. A vast majority still considers anime music as cute music that might not have much meaning. Nevertheless, in the recent years, one can find traces of jazz, rock and many other elements in anime music. By exposing people to anime music that is similar to other widely-listened music, the project could bring awareness to the diversity of anime music and therefore even piques interests in the anime industry itself. Thus, the target audience of the application is those who are explorative and want to identify other sources of music that fit their taste.</p> <p>For more details, refer to <a href="https://github.com/simonzhu97/2022-Spotify-Anime-music-Recommender">this GitHub repository</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="AI"/><category term="Machine_Learning"/><category term="AWS"/><category term="Music"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spotify Anime Music Recommender]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Generating Harmonious Melody with AI</title><link href="https://simonzhu97.github.io/blog/2021/AI-music/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Generating Harmonious Melody with AI"/><published>2021-03-20T21:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-20T21:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://simonzhu97.github.io/blog/2021/AI-music</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://simonzhu97.github.io/blog/2021/AI-music/"><![CDATA[<p>Music generation is an emerging field in artificial intelligence. It allows musicians and music lovers to compose music when they lack inspirations as well as to enjoy music in the style they desire. Existing projects like Magenta have successfully generated polyphony based on a given monophony. However, none has particularly focused on a two-line polyphony creation, or duet creation. Since the duet composition is a very common and useful practice for musicians, we intend to create an Artificial Intelligence that can transform one line of monophonic melody into a two-line polyphonic melody using Magenta’s Polyphony RNN Generator and Q-learning. It takes in one line of music without accompanying chords, creates another monophonic melody that harmonizes with the input melody, and eventually outputs the resulting combined polyphonic melody. By doing this, we aim to provide one elementary solution to the problem of automatic music creation.</p> <p>The following video showcases the original monophonic piece of music and the polyphonic piece generated by our AI.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <iframe src="https://youtu.be/cKzO6WTX7_o" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="auto" height="auto"/> </figure> </div> </div> <p>If you are interested in the specific techniques we used during the project, please refer to the <a href="https://github.com/simonzhu97/AI_PROJECT">repository</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="AI"/><category term="AI"/><category term="Music"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI project to generate melodies]]></summary></entry></feed>